<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cyprus &#8211; Milo Ame: Random Thoughts</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/cyprus/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 22:44:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Screaming in Silence</title>
		<link>/screaming-in-silence/</link>
					<comments>/screaming-in-silence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Milo Ame]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 22:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Emotions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyprus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loneliness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The night was filled with silence, only to be interrupted by their occasional laughters. As the distance between us grew further, the laughters faded. The brightly-lit street was returned its calmness. I was never a stranger to being left behind. Actually, with twelve years of practice, I am somewhat a master. But maybe it’s the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The night was filled with silence, only to be interrupted by their occasional laughters. As the distance between us grew further, the laughters faded. The brightly-lit street was returned its calmness.</p>



<p>I was never a stranger to being left behind. Actually, with twelve years of practice, I am somewhat a master. But maybe it’s the influence of the alcohol, or maybe it’s the sense of loneliness and homesickness that creeps up in starless nights like this, this feeling hits particularly hard. I say feeling, because I can’t exactly describe it. A mixture of shamefulness, self-pity, and loneliness, I guess.</p>



<p>I silently calculated if I turn at one of the countless intersections, would they notice if I’m gone? I wasn’t trying to gain their attention. Quite the opposite, I wished they forgot about me. And I would roam around the streets, appreciating the silence, with the chill spring wind accompanying me. I find comfort in this poetic loneliness.</p>



<p>As they were about to disappear from my sight, they stopped, turned their head and waited. Their conversation halted, like respectful audiences in the cinema startled by the sudden beginning of a movie. They watched as I limped through the fifty meters between us. I was consciously aware of how broken I looked, with my hips unnaturally twisting with every step I took. But I am the only character featured on the silver screen,so I maintained a smile, hoping to hide shame and apology with casual confidence.</p>



<p>As soon as I reached them, they turned around and resumed walking. The distance again started to grow. He turned, noticed and slowed down. He offered me a hand. Although I didn’t need it or even want it, I took it, as I didn’t have the heart to reject his kindness.</p>



<p>His steps were fast. His hands dragging me, attempting to keep up with them. The distance again slowly started to grow. He shouted something, responding to a joke they made. That evoked a response, yet not enough for them to slow down and include him back in the conversation. He eventually gave up, because of the heavy burden he was now carrying.</p>



<p>Their laughter once again fades. The brightly-lit street was returned its silence.</p>



<p>“You’re quiet.” Unable to bear the sudden calmness, he said.</p>



<p>Bursting with shame and anger, I wanted to yell “Go. If you want to join them, go. I’m not a charity case. I walk fine by myself.”</p>



<p>But as I glanced at the warm lights shining on the old city wall, it felt cruel to break the night’s soft calmness. I pushed back the tears in my eyes, and answered, “just tired, I guess.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/screaming-in-silence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>不堪之地</title>
		<link>/far-far-away-behind-the-word-mountains/</link>
					<comments>/far-far-away-behind-the-word-mountains/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Milo Ame]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 21:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Nicosia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyprus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/veenv2/?p=76</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[往常度过周末两日要约东约西，不知不觉安排从早到晚，因为空闲的两日让自己感觉无比的空虚。但繁忙的每日中却又怀念起空闲的生活，期盼在温馨的屋里边酌红酒边赏电影，抑或欣赏未曾相识的街道与建筑，抑或在正午树荫下赏读散文，体会宁静适宜的心境。]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>往常度过周末两日要约东约西，不知不觉安排从早到晚，因为空闲的两日让自己感觉无比的空虚。但繁忙的每日中却又怀念起空闲的生活，期盼在温馨的屋里边酌红酒边赏电影，抑或欣赏未曾相识的街道与建筑，抑或在正午树荫下赏读散文，体会宁静适宜的心境。</p>



<p>这个周末同样试图约东约西，可惜于在这城市好友不多，且无人愿同我享受宁静的午后。我不愿浪费这明媚且懒散的阳光，又想起往常对空闲的向往，便随手抽出一册散文，独自走向城中。计划在咖啡厅阅读，寻找宁静的心境。</p>



<p>我的目的地是相当安详的。每当游客探索此城，到达这片区域总会停下脚步，穿梭于巷中。虽建筑不同西欧一样壮观，墙皮常常脱落透露出内垢的红砖，搭配着灿烂的红花与茂盛的绿荫，则是另一般美。相比于豪华且令人敬畏的西欧建筑，我是更喜欢这粗糙的美。在隐蔽的庭院中，绿草红花之中相坐，背景中缓缓播放西洋爵士，比在嘈杂的西班牙Cafetería或是做作的网红中国咖啡厅总是悠闲舒适的多。</p>



<p>要到达这目的地，却要穿过嘈杂的半现代化街道。这街道中布满新建的矮楼，狭窄的柏油路，完全失去了历史的痕迹。矮楼底层均是落地玻璃窗，可以想象陈列着鲜艳的衣着或精致的蛋糕，透窗可见闲人谈笑的情景。不知是否因为疫情的打击，这些矮楼商铺大部分大门紧闭，玻璃窗布满灰尘。若留意透过窗观察内部，只见被遗弃的陈旧家具堆放在角落。而仅剩的商铺则不加修饰，咖啡厅和餐厅仿佛空档的大学食堂，便利店狭小阴暗，破旧纸箱堆放在角落。路过几座矮楼则是铁丝网围起的废墟，或是作为停车场的凹凸不平的沙地。我说半现代化，是因这区域埋藏了历史的痕迹，追求现代都市的繁华，却最终落为两不像，只剩一片萧条。这也是我刚初到达这都市的第一印象，也怪不得众多好友见此便苦不堪言，不愿在此岛久留。</p>



<p>然而这半现代化街道却是我到达巷中或是拜访好友的必经之路，最初我同一般游客，抓紧脚步离开这不堪之地。然而路过多了，便开始留意这些其貌不扬的店铺。店铺多由当地移民所有，招牌上常写清真，印度美食或非洲杂货。上次在这区域游荡是因好友寻找超市中没有的食材，便拜访了几家杂货店。路上我被一家阴暗空旷的餐馆所吸引，便鼓起勇气进入参观。正当我观摩罕见的甜点，老板介绍其自于巴基斯坦。因好奇心所趋我便买了几小块品尝。品完一点后才意识到其甜腻，便将其提回家，终究被遗忘在冰箱里度完余生。</p>



<p>游荡久了，便被好奇心所趋，梦想进入每一家餐厅或咖啡厅品尝世界各地之滋味。此处也就不再是路途而变成终点。回想起刚到此处对其的厌恶，感觉终究是不公平的。的确此区域不如西欧的壮观和严肃，亦不如古巷的悠闲与安详。但这空虚萧条中却隐藏了可贵的多元文化。阴暗的餐厅中隐藏了各地美食，狭隘的店铺中充满了不同语言的对话。我曾经感叹西班牙小镇虽美但文化过于单一，如今却在这看似丑陋的街道遇见了所寻。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/far-far-away-behind-the-word-mountains/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
