<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Loneliness &#8211; Milo Ame: Random Thoughts</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/loneliness/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 22:01:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Screaming in Silence</title>
		<link>/screaming-in-silence/</link>
					<comments>/screaming-in-silence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Milo Ame]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 22:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Emotions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyprus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loneliness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The night was filled with silence, only to be interrupted by their occasional laughters. As the distance between us grew further, the laughters faded. The brightly-lit street was returned its calmness. I was never a stranger to being left behind. Actually, with twelve years of practice, I am somewhat a master. But maybe it’s the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The night was filled with silence, only to be interrupted by their occasional laughters. As the distance between us grew further, the laughters faded. The brightly-lit street was returned its calmness.</p>



<p>I was never a stranger to being left behind. Actually, with twelve years of practice, I am somewhat a master. But maybe it’s the influence of the alcohol, or maybe it’s the sense of loneliness and homesickness that creeps up in starless nights like this, this feeling hits particularly hard. I say feeling, because I can’t exactly describe it. A mixture of shamefulness, self-pity, and loneliness, I guess.</p>



<p>I silently calculated if I turn at one of the countless intersections, would they notice if I’m gone? I wasn’t trying to gain their attention. Quite the opposite, I wished they forgot about me. And I would roam around the streets, appreciating the silence, with the chill spring wind accompanying me. I find comfort in this poetic loneliness.</p>



<p>As they were about to disappear from my sight, they stopped, turned their head and waited. Their conversation halted, like respectful audiences in the cinema startled by the sudden beginning of a movie. They watched as I limped through the fifty meters between us. I was consciously aware of how broken I looked, with my hips unnaturally twisting with every step I took. But I am the only character featured on the silver screen,so I maintained a smile, hoping to hide shame and apology with casual confidence.</p>



<p>As soon as I reached them, they turned around and resumed walking. The distance again started to grow. He turned, noticed and slowed down. He offered me a hand. Although I didn’t need it or even want it, I took it, as I didn’t have the heart to reject his kindness.</p>



<p>His steps were fast. His hands dragging me, attempting to keep up with them. The distance again slowly started to grow. He shouted something, responding to a joke they made. That evoked a response, yet not enough for them to slow down and include him back in the conversation. He eventually gave up, because of the heavy burden he was now carrying.</p>



<p>Their laughter once again fades. The brightly-lit street was returned its silence.</p>



<p>“You’re quiet.” Unable to bear the sudden calmness, he said.</p>



<p>Bursting with shame and anger, I wanted to yell “Go. If you want to join them, go. I’m not a charity case. I walk fine by myself.”</p>



<p>But as I glanced at the warm lights shining on the old city wall, it felt cruel to break the night’s soft calmness. I pushed back the tears in my eyes, and answered, “just tired, I guess.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/screaming-in-silence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
