<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sleep &#8211; Milo Ame: Random Thoughts</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/sleep/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 22:03:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Living with an overly active mind &#8211; even when sleeping</title>
		<link>/living-with-an-overly-active-mind-even-when-sleeping/</link>
					<comments>/living-with-an-overly-active-mind-even-when-sleeping/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Milo Ame]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 22:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sleep]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a long and exhausting day, I finally laid on my bed. My tense body, upon touching the cool and clean sheet of the bed, relaxes. For a brief moment, I feel relaxed, comfortable, at ease. And then the dread creeps in.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After a long and exhausting day, I finally laid on my bed. My tense body, upon touching the cool and clean sheet of the bed, relaxes. For a brief moment, I feel relaxed, comfortable, at ease. </p>



<p>And then the dread creeps in. It takes the form of noticing. During this calm moment, I take notice of my surrounding sounds. The sound of the cold air coming out from the AC. The music playing by my neighbors. The slamming of the door in the hallway. </p>



<p>And then I focus on it. How can I sleep with these sounds constantly in the background? The urge to get rid of these sounds start to surface. Some times, I lie in bed hoping the urge will go away, and that I accidentally focus on other things and fall asleep. Most of the time, it doesn&#8217;t work. I get up and I try to change it: turning down the AC fan or knocking on the neighbor&#8217;s doors and asking them to quiet down. </p>



<p>But sometimes, I can&#8217;t change it, as it&#8217;s something out of my control. Other times, changing it throws me into a cycle of constantly wanting to change other things and everything. </p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Meditation</strong></p>



<p>So many people have told me that meditation helps a lot of anxiety and sleep, and there are some scientific evidences that backs this up. I have been practicing meditation long before my sleep anxiety has become a problem. When the anxiety really became a serious issue this year, meditation doesn&#8217;t seem to be helping much.</p>



<p>In fact, I looked online, some people were saying that meditation makes their sleeping worse. And if you want to talk science &#8211; there are research that finds this too.</p>



<p>The more I think about it, the more I find meditation to address <em>my kind of</em> insomnia/anxiety counterintuitive &#8211; specifically the technique of <strong>focused attention</strong>, which is the foundation of many meditation practices. This technique requires the mediator to focus on their breathes. As soon as they realize that their mind has wandered off, they acknowledge it, and return their attention back to the breathes. </p>



<p>However, this is exactly how my kind of sleep anxiety manifests itself. Sleeping requires the mind to drift off. At night, I often involuntarily focus on the undesirable sound, and as soon as I realize my mind has wandered off, I remind my brain that the threat (the sound) is still there, and I jolt awake. In this case, it seems that practicing focused attention train the mind to go through this particular pathway. In fact, I don&#8217;t even know my sleep anxiety was caused or exacerbated by this practice. </p>



<p>Of course, this is not to dismiss all meditation practices. For me, I found the following practices beneficial:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Body scan</strong>: When my anxiety starts and my heart rate start pulsing, body scan brings me back into the moment. Specifically, I let myself feel every part of my body is heavy, and I let them relax deep into the bed. </li>



<li><strong>Noting</strong>: Noting works when the anxious thoughts have not overtaken completely (by this point I should just get up and distract myself). When I notice the anxious thoughts start coming up (often characterized by the overly-focus on any specific sound), I note the sounds as anxiety, and let them go, and go back to the original state of peace.</li>



<li><strong>Yoga</strong>: Although I haven&#8217;t tried practicing Yoga at bed time (but I should), every time after practicing Yoga I feel restored and peaceful, which sitting meditation has often failed for me.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/living-with-an-overly-active-mind-even-when-sleeping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
