<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Travel &#8211; Milo Ame: Thoughts</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/travel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 17:41:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Far far away, behind the word mountains</title>
		<link>/far-far-away-behind-the-word-mountains/</link>
					<comments>/far-far-away-behind-the-word-mountains/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[zaaron345]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 01:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/veenv2/?p=76</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A mountain is a large landform that rises above the surrounding land in a limited area, usually in the form of a peak. A mountain is generally steeper than a hill. Mountains are formed through tectonic forces or volcanism. These forces can locally raise the surface of the earth. Mountains erode slowly through the action [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A mountain is a large landform that rises above the surrounding land in a limited area, usually in the form of a peak. A mountain is generally steeper than a hill. <strong>Mountains </strong>are formed through tectonic forces or volcanism. </p>



<p>These forces can locally raise the surface of the earth. Mountains erode slowly through the action of rivers, <a href="#">weather conditions</a>, and glaciers. A few mountains are isolated summits, but most occur in huge <strong>mountain ranges</strong>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/veenv2/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/chris-lawton-c0rIh0nFTFU-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-414" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/chris-lawton-c0rIh0nFTFU-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/chris-lawton-c0rIh0nFTFU-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/chris-lawton-c0rIh0nFTFU-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/chris-lawton-c0rIh0nFTFU-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/chris-lawton-c0rIh0nFTFU-unsplash-100x67.jpg 100w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/chris-lawton-c0rIh0nFTFU-unsplash-675x450.jpg 675w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/chris-lawton-c0rIh0nFTFU-unsplash.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>High elevations on mountains produce colder climates than at sea level. These colder climates strongly affect the ecosystems of mountains: different elevations have different plants and animals. Because of the less hospitable terrain and climate, mountains tend to be used <strong>less for agriculture</strong> and more for resource extraction and recreation, such as mountain climbing.</p>



<p>The highest mountain on <strong>Earth </strong>is <strong>Mount Everest</strong> in the <strong>Himalayas of Asia</strong>, whose summit is 8,850 m (29,035 ft) above mean sea level. The highest known mountain on any planet in the <a href="#">Solar System</a> is Olympus Mons on Mars at 21,171 m (69,459 ft).</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Definition</h2>



<p>There is no universally accepted definition of a mountain. Elevation, volume, relief, steepness, spacing and continuity have been used as criteria for defining a mountain. In the <strong>Oxford English Dictionary</strong> a mountain is defined as &#8220;a natural elevation of the earth surface rising more or less abruptly from the surrounding level and attaining an altitude which, relatively to the adjacent elevation, is impressive or notable.&#8221;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="597" src="http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/veenv2/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/alex-cKH9F7Wjn9U-unsplash-1024x597.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-498" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/alex-cKH9F7Wjn9U-unsplash-1024x597.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/alex-cKH9F7Wjn9U-unsplash-300x175.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/alex-cKH9F7Wjn9U-unsplash-768x448.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/alex-cKH9F7Wjn9U-unsplash-1536x896.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/alex-cKH9F7Wjn9U-unsplash-100x58.jpg 100w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/alex-cKH9F7Wjn9U-unsplash-700x408.jpg 700w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/alex-cKH9F7Wjn9U-unsplash.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pink paper over blue background</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Whether a landform is called a mountain may depend on local usage. Mount Scott outside Lawton, <strong>Oklahoma, USA</strong>, is only 251 m (823 ft) from its base to its highest point. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Physical Geography states &#8220;Some authorities regard eminences above 600 metres (2,000 ft) as mountains, those below being referred to as hills.&#8221;</p>
<cite> Whittow&#8217;s Dictionary </cite></blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Geology</h2>



<p>There are <strong>three main types of mountains</strong>:&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Volcano">volcanic</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fold_mountain">fold</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fault-block_mountain">block</a>.&nbsp;All three types are formed from&nbsp;plate tectonics: when portions of the Earth&#8217;s crust <strong>move</strong>, <strong>crumple</strong>, and <strong>dive</strong>. Compressional forces,&nbsp;isostatic&nbsp;uplift&nbsp;and intrusion of&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Igneous_rock">igneous matter</a>&nbsp;forces surface rock upward, creating a landform higher than the surrounding features. The height of the feature makes it either a hill or, if higher and steeper, a mountain. Major mountains tend to occur in <strong>long linear arcs</strong>, indicating tectonic plate boundaries and activity. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Volcanoes</h3>



<p><strong>Volcanoes </strong>are formed when&nbsp;a plate is <strong>pushed below another plate</strong>, or at a&nbsp;mid-ocean ridge&nbsp;or&nbsp;hotspot.&nbsp;At a depth of around 100&nbsp;km, melting occurs in rock above the slab (due to the addition of water), and forms&nbsp;magma&nbsp;that reaches the surface. When the magma reaches the surface, it often builds a volcanic mountain, such as a&nbsp;shield volcano&nbsp;or a&nbsp;stratovolcano.&nbsp;<strong>Examples of volcanoes</strong> include&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Fuji">Mount Fuji</a>&nbsp;in Japan and&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Pinatubo">Mount Pinatubo</a>&nbsp;in the Philippines. The magma does not have to reach the surface in order to create a mountain: magma that solidifies below ground can still form&nbsp;dome mountains, such as&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navajo_Mountain">Navajo Mountain</a>&nbsp;in the US. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Fold mountains</h3>



<p><strong>Fold mountains</strong> occur when two plates collide: shortening occurs along thrust faults and the crust is overthickened.&nbsp;Since the less dense&nbsp;continental crust&nbsp;&#8220;floats&#8221; on the denser&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mantle_(geology)">mantle</a>&nbsp;rocks beneath, the weight of any crustal material forced upward to form hills,&nbsp;plateaus&nbsp;or mountains must be&nbsp;balanced by the buoyancy force&nbsp;of a much greater volume forced downward into the mantle. Thus the continental crust is normally much thicker under mountains, compared to lower lying areas.&nbsp;Rock can&nbsp;fold&nbsp;either <strong>symmetrically </strong>or <strong>asymmetrically</strong>. The upfolds are&nbsp;anticlines&nbsp;and the downfolds are&nbsp;synclines: in asymmetric folding there may also be recumbent and overturned folds. The&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Balkan_Mountains">Balkan Mountains</a>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jura_Mountains">Jura Mountains</a>&nbsp;are examples of fold mountains. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="602" src="http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/veenv2/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/gareth-harper-yACpBcInUos-unsplash-1024x602.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-441" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/gareth-harper-yACpBcInUos-unsplash-1024x602.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/gareth-harper-yACpBcInUos-unsplash-300x176.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/gareth-harper-yACpBcInUos-unsplash-768x451.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/gareth-harper-yACpBcInUos-unsplash-1536x902.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/gareth-harper-yACpBcInUos-unsplash-100x59.jpg 100w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/gareth-harper-yACpBcInUos-unsplash-700x411.jpg 700w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/gareth-harper-yACpBcInUos-unsplash.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">This is a example caption</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Block mountains</h3>



<p>B<strong>lock mountains</strong> are caused by&nbsp;faults&nbsp;in the crust: a plane where rocks have moved past each other. When rocks on one side of a fault rise relative to the other, it can form a mountain.&nbsp;The uplifted blocks are <strong>block mountains</strong> or&nbsp;<strong>horsts</strong>. The intervening dropped blocks are termed&nbsp;graben: these can be small or form extensive&nbsp;rift valley&nbsp;systems. This form of&nbsp;landscape&nbsp;can be seen in&nbsp;East Africa, the&nbsp;Vosges, the&nbsp;Basin and Range Province&nbsp;of <strong>Western North America</strong> and the&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rhine_graben">Rhine</a>&nbsp;valley. These areas often occur when the regional stress is extensional and the&nbsp;crust&nbsp;is thinned. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/far-far-away-behind-the-word-mountains/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
